people who lived on the territory of Rus' here is
люди которые жили на территории Руси вот
Kyiv There and so on Yes those people who
Киев Там и так дальше Да те люди которые
now live in the Zhytomyr region in
сейчас живут в Житомирской области в
Kyiv are essentially their Heirs
Киевской это ж по сути ихние Наследники
Yes people yes people who lived in there
Да люди да люди которые жили в там
Vladimir region Yes these Finno-
Владимирской области Да вот эти фино
Ugric tribes people who now
угорские племена люди которые сейчас там
live there are their
живут это ихний
Heir Hello where are you from I am from St.
Наследник Здравствуйте Вы откуда Я из
Petersburg and you are cool I see you are on your
Питера а вы прикольно Я вижу вы с вами
side Yes you are Russian I am an atheist No well it
бок Да вы русский я атеист Не ну вот там
says there You are Russian God is with you Yes it
написано Вы русский с вами Бог Да там
says there I am from Rostov But I have been living in
написано Я сам из Ростова Но живу в
Brussels for 18 years in 2 years in the
Брюсселе уже 18 лет через 2 года
twentieth I support Ukraine simply And
двадцатом поддерживаю Украину просто А
why just wondering why I live in
почему просто интересно почему живу в
Brussels or Why I support Ukraine
Брюсселе или Почему поддерживаю Украину
not Why do you support Ukraine without
не Почему поддерживаешь Украину без
because yes yes because look I lived in
потому да да потому что смотри я жил в
Rostov yes I live in Europe 18 years I see
Ростове да живу в Европе 18 лет я вижу
what a democratic world is and I understand
что такое демократический мир и понимаю
that Russia by attacking Ukraine acts as an
что Россия напав на Украину выступает
aggressor Armed Forces one with this yes And I
агрессором ВС одно с это да А я в Ростов
will go to Rostov in March And what will you do there for
поеду в марте А что там будешь делать на
football and for football
футбол а на футбол
hell hooligan no no hoo I just love to
ада хулиган не не ху просто люблю
watch sectors I love  and so I'm like from St.
смотреть сектора люблю а так я типа из
Petersburg and we have like Zenit playing
Питера а у нас типа Зенит играет с
Rostov in May And you
Ростовом май А ты
look
смотри
like yes yes I see like well you're an imperialist who are
типа да да я вижу типа ну ты имперец кто
you I'm just a nationalist I like without I don't
ты Я просто националист я типа без не
like it when someone stops someone that
люблю когда кто-то кому-то пресекает что
let's do it like this Which of the famous
давайте хош давай так Какие из известных
Russian nationalists are closer to
там националистов российских ближе к
you in ideas not at all to be honest
тебе по идеям не вообще честно говоря у
we don't have that at all that is Well
нас вообще нет такого то есть Ну
for example there was Tisa there is
например там был тиса есть там
this one there it's like for me the
этот это как по мне
Kremlin
кремл
is good cream
хоро крем
Demushkin I
дёмушкин
don't know that not me so purely I don't like
этого не знаю не я так чисто Я не люблю
these cults of personality As for me it's
вот эти культы личностей Как по мне это
not that better to go myself that is
не то лучше типа самому идти то есть ну
well okay let's do it
хорошо давай так
Uh what Whose ideas are closer to you Yes so that I
Ээ какие Чьи идеи тебе ближе Да чтобы я
understand Well what's in your head Well
понял Ну что у тебя в голове Ну вот у
I don't have that that is well I
меня такого нету то есть ну я и прямо
can't call me there directly Maxim a
нельзя меня называть там прямо Максимом
politician just a person who is like that
политиком просто человек который такой
well I'll read I'm interested that is I am that and
ну почитаю мне интересно то есть я та а
what What are you reading here What are you reading becoming
что Что читаешь вот Что читаешь став
now I'm reading about Well Vla
сейчас читаю про Ну вла
and Vlasov I think you know yes Andrey Vlasov
а Власова думаю знаешь да Андрей Власов
yes yes now about him I'm reading And what exactly are
да да сейчас про него Читаю А что именно
you reading now  I'll show you where it was here well
читаешь сейчас покажу где тут была ну
there it's called General I think it's called There it's
там это генерал по-моему называется Там
simply described How everything was with Mua I
просто описывается Как всё было с Муа
used to read these books in Dan language I used to read German Memoirs that is
бывало читал Мемуары немецкие то есть
so
тако
different Shmelev
разно шмелёва
no And who else do you read from ideologists from
не А кого ещё читаешь из идеологов из
ideologists no that is I from philosophy
идеологов нет то есть я из философии
If you take then I read only Hegel
Если брать то читал только Гегеля
philosophy of law and this horse Mass and
философия права и этого коне Масса и
power in my opinion philosophy everything If I'm not
власть по-моему философии всё Если не
mistaken Well yes stories What ideas of Hegel do
ошибаюсь Ну да истории Какие идеи Гегеля
you have more than
тебе более
BMI hundred in general for
ИМТ ста вообще для
that an interesting philosopher was possible
та интересный философ был возможно
Because it's really hard to
Потому что его действительно тяжело
read that is there's a lot of tautology
читать то есть са очень много тавтологии
That is when you read there a few
То есть когда ты читаешь там несколько
pages and there the word will is repeated
страниц а там слово воли повторяется раз
30 times this is well this is probably the peculiarities of
30 это ну это наверное особенности
translation or German it's not the point
перевода либо Немецкого не дело в том
that let's say philosophical schools of the 20th and
что скажем философские школы x x и
early 20th centuries they gravitated towards such let's
начала XX века они тя готели к таким
say
скажем
overly hyper construction instead of
излишне гипер конструкция вместо того
writing something briefly and clearly yes
чтобы написать что-то коротко и ясно да
they packed it into such there it's an
они это упаковывали в такие там это же
element like magic you know For example a
элемент как магия понимаешь Вот например
priest should say something like that so
священник как-то так должен сказать
that it would be mysterious so that  grandmother then
чтобы было загадочно чтобы бабушка потом
this day thought that he wanted to convey this
это день думала что он хотел донести эту
idea he there instead of saying
мысль он там вместо того чтобы сказать
not to steal Yes he
не Укради Да он
says robbing someone else's
говорит обирание чужого
property and so on Well yes this is a problem
имущества и проче Ну да это проблема вот
exactly of those years well those centuries even
именно тех годов ну тех столетий даже
Yeah that then and just writers like
Угу что тогда и просто писатели вот тот
Tolstoy there Toms like these are
же Толстой там Томы вот такие читать
impossible to read And so in general I by the way honestly
невозможно А так вообще я кстати честно
Well now I don't know how to
говоря Ну сейчас я не знаю как в
travel around Europe in the current realities
нынешних реалиях путешествовать по
Although there is a chance to get a visa and
Европе Хотя шанс получить визу есть а
so in principle there as you only in
так в принципе там как ты только в
Belgium Here was yes Brussels Belgium not me
Бельгии Вот был да брюсель Бельгии не я
Well we have the Schengen zone you go wherever
Ну у нас же Шенгенская зона ездишь куда
you want and yes There is
хочешь а да Там
no in the euro I want with But I'm waiting for
же нет в евро хочу съ А вот жду то что
something to end by that no they
может что-нибудь закончится к тому не
will not let you out they will not let you in here for
уже не будут выпускать вас не будут сюда
10 years probably not Well
пускать ничего лет 10 наверное не Ну
some travel I know that you
некоторые путешествуют я знаю то что
can travel from Russia but there is a
можно из России путешествует но там есть
problem with getting a visa they will not
проблема с получением визы дадут не
give Schengen Well if Tepa representatives of the
дадут Шенген Ну если Тепа представители
LGBT community then they can give Well this is
ЛГБТ сообщества то могут дать Ну это
clearly not your option I understand yes And
явно не твой вариант я так понимаю да А
so I would not want that is well for me the
так не хотелось бы то есть ну для меня
advantage is just  some
преимуществе это как раз какая-нибудь
Spain
там Испания
England And what attracts there firstly in
Англия А что привлекает там во-первых в
principle I like to go
принципе нравится ездить куда-то
somewhere to see a landmark that
смотреть там достопримечательность то
is in Germany I really want the Wewelsburg castle
есть в Германии Я очень хочу замок
And why it well I just read about it
А почему его ну просто я про него
firstly in books that's where I
во-первых читал в книгах именно там
came across this when for example
сталкивался с этим когда вот например
I read about German occultism during the Reich
читал про немецкий оккультизм врем Рейха
plus I have
вот плюс у меня есть
German leaflets of the war and there is one
немецки листовки войны и там есть одна
of the stoves from the web
из печа из вебу как
just like that and so football pos European
раз вот а так футбол пос Европейский
football So listen I understand that you
футбол Так слушай я так понимаю то ты
read the history of the Tuli society there
читал историю там общества
Well in the Third Reich there was a
Тули котора Ну в третьем рейхе было
mystical society
мистическое общество
turr this would be an organization by itself
турр это само собой бы организация была
And the Tu society this is before Hitler came to
А Общество ту это е до прихода Гитлера к
power was
власти было
not me that's where it's mainly about how
не я именно вот там в основном про как
Himmler led it All this
этим руководил гиммлер Вот это всё то
that he is basically this shift about
что он же в основном это сдвига про
occultism and all that Do you
оккультизм все дела Как ты
think it would be better for Russia to create a separate
считаешь России лучше создать отдельную
Russian Republic Yes so that there would be a
русскую Республику Да чтобы было Вот
Russian national state Yes and to
Русское национальное государство Да и
pull in all these other nationalities from itself
обтянуть от себя все вот эти другие
yes Or to remain an empire with
народности да Или оставаться империи с
different peoples
разными народами
but so that the Russian identity
но чтоб русская идентичность
Well  I am for the preservation of the territory That's exactly it
Ну я за сохранность территории Это точно
I have here in terms of Russian nationalism
тут у меня в плане национализма русского
I have more of a claim to migrants from
у меня больше претензия к мигрантам из
abroad Central Asia Caucasus and so
за рубежа Средней Азии Кавказ вот а так
well in principle the Russian population it
ну в принципе русское население оно в
mainly lives in Central Russia that
основном живёт в Центральной России то
is there especially Well if it were not for migrants
есть там особо Вот если бы не мигранты
specifically and Central Asia there would be no problems at all
именно и Средней Азии проблем бы вообще
and so the fact that we have other
не было а так то что у нас со другие
nationalities is not a problem at all look
народности вообще не проблема смотри
if we look at migrants from Chechnya
если мы смотрим мигранты из Чечни
Dagestan they also prevail already in the
Дагестана они тоже превалируют уже в
central cities that's right
центральных городах это да Вот именно
Chechnya is the problem these are the only
Чечня - это проблема это единственные
internal migrants who are not
внутренние мигранты которые не
satisfied Well it seems to me that
устраивают Ну как мне кажется что
Dagestan also already feels itself
Дагестан уже тоже себя ощущает
quite tightly on its feet in comparison with the
довольно плотно ногах в сравнени с
Russians Well what about Dagestan now That's
русскими Да ну что сейчас Дагестана Вот
in connection with this Karo all the business There is too
в связи с этим Каро все дела Там слишком
much freedom given That is this I
много Свободы дано То есть это Считаю
already consider as
уже как
Independent as a country in the country pain
Независимо как страна в стране боль
more than that they are actually independent Yes
больше того они фактически независимы Да
but Moscow feeds them Moscow throws
но Москва и их кормит Москва кидает
so much money into Chechnya it turns out
столько денег в Чечню получается вроде
as if they won the war they say Yes but for
как бы выиграли войну говорят Да но
some reason Tribute pays che well  yes, this is a
почему-то Дань плат че ну это да это
big problem from Rania's point of view,
большая проблема с точки зрения Рания
it's going badly in terms of the fact that it's
он плохо идт в плане того то что из
not going to the local treasury from the regions, but that it's
регионов идт не в местную казну а то что
all going to Moscow, where it's distributed,
всё идт в Москву там распределяется
of course, and who are you by
большей части идёт конечно же А ты по
profession? I'm still nowhere, like, I'll go
профессии кто я ещё нигде типа я пойду
to be a trainer. And who did you work for in my
на тренера А работал кем вообще в своей
life? I've worked in very few places now,
жизни я сейчас работать мало где успел
that is, I've worked in such primitive
то есть работал ну в таких примитивных
jobs. And what do you think? Do
работах а как ты счита
Russians have one, maximum two
наме у руских есть один максимум два
children in a family? Yes, for
ребёнка в семье Да
example, there's Chechnya. And so on. Yes,
у например там Чечня И так дальше да у
they have five. The Tatars have three. Yes, through. Well, yes,
них там пять у татар трое Да через Ну да
because, in principle, this is a problem.
потому что ну это в принципе проблема
Plus, it's not only that, even in the
плюс это не только даже вот так вот в
National Plan, it's seen
Национальном плане просматривается а то
that the poor, as a rule, have a lot of
что у бедных как правило гораздо куча
children living in a one-room apartment, there in
детей живут в однушке там в
five because the Russians put their
пятером потому что русские они ставят
career first, then the
сначала карьера потом уже
children. Well, I don't know what the
дети там же Ну бедности не знаю какая
logic is about poverty. But, for example, in Chechnya and in
там логика А вот например в Чечне и в
other such countries, this is precisely a
других таких странах это именно
religious issue. The fact that such people
религиозный вопрос то что такие вот Во
will pay for the glory of Allah is
Славу Аллаха будем
cool,
платиться прикольно
strange. This is a problem. Yes, the fact that the Russian
странно это проблема да то что русских
birth rate is very low. Are
очень маленький коэффициент рождае
you going to do this?  I do
ты собираешься это
n't fix it in principle I might
исправлять не я в принципе я может быть
even be for the separation of Chechnya I don't
даже за отделение Чечни не
know why why Chechnya Yes and
знаю а почему а почему Чечни Да а
Tatarstan and Bashkartastan
Татарстан и башкартастан
no well there are no such problems with them that is
нет ну с ними таких проблем нет то есть
about the Tatars There are few such stories that
про татар Мало таких историй то что
something some kind of
что-то какой-нибудь
crime Tatars lived
криминал татары прожит
with you in the same state Why do
смм с вами в одном государстве Зачем
you need to be in the same state with the Tatars
тебе быть в одном государстве с татарами
No well I don't know how it would turn out like that to
Не ну я не знаю как сложилось бы вот так
guess it is impossible to say for sure As
загадывать нельзя сказать что точно Как
for me if some specific
по мне если какая-то определённая
republic of Russia becomes
республика России станет
independent I would not be sure in their
независимой я бы не уверен в их
economic plan that everything will be
экономическом плане то что всё будет
fine because of course we don't have
хорошо пото что не есть конечно у нас
regions that are industrial Nuri Dava Moscow of
области которы пром Нури Дава Москва
all regions resource any region without
всех регионов ресурс любой регион без
Moscow will be
Москвы будет
richer Well it's not a fact that it will
богаче Ну не факт именно то что так
turn out like that But in principle this is the
получится Но в принципе вот это
wrong policy that is well I am for the fact that
неправильная политика то есть ну я за то
I
чтобы вот я
myself am from a small very poor republic and
сам из неболь весьма бедной республики и
oh republic region now I am in St. Petersburg
ой республики области сейчас я в Питере
in general I am from the Novgorod region and under the
вообще я из Новгородской области и при
current workshop it is not developing at all and
нынешних цех она прям не развивается и
so money
так деньги
Although the Novgorod region is almost
Хотя Новгородская область это ж почти
Europe Yes  this is
Европа Да это
nearby this is the former
рядом это бывшая
capital here and so there is there is
столица вот а так есть там вообще
no development at all what capital
развития нет никакого какая столица
Novgorod was not the capital of Russia
Новгород не был столицы России
Novgorod Rus I mean not
Новгородской Руси имею виду не
Novgorod Rus there was no such thing Rus
Новгородской Руси не было такого Русь
was only one was not Novgorodskaya ru
была только одна не была Новгородская ру
Rus Novgorod Republic I apologize
Русь Новгородская республика извиняюсь
here is the republic republic republic plus even
вот республика респуб республи плюс ещ
before the annexation received
до присоединения получа
when Well before they came to Kyiv
когда Ну до того как Киеву пришли ещ
Novgorod was still like such an
Новгород был как бы таким
independent Kyiv Novgorod
независимым Киева Новгорода не
was not no Novgorod no Novgorod Kyiv was already like
было нет новгоро нет Киев был уже как
exactly this as a city I mean
именно этот как город Я имею в виду то
that at first they came to
что сначала же пришли в
reign in Novgorod as a prince from there already in
князе княжить в Новгород оттуда уже в
kitsch this is the only Only such is
китчи это Единственно Только такое
written in the Tale of Bygone Years which he
написано в Повести временных лет которое
wrote
писал
from the Novgorod region you know that
из Новгородской области знае что
archeology does not find Novgorod
археология не находит Новгороде
settlements there Slavic de And so on for
поселении там славянских де И так дальше
centuries yes that is Novgorod why
века да то есть Новгород почему
is Novgorod called What does
называется Новгород Что означает
Novgorod mean New Year New city yes that
Новгород Новый Год Новый город да то
is if there is Novgorod then it was an
есть если есть Новгород значит был
old city True Well as far as we know that
старый город Правда Ну насколько зна что
with
с
moisture already Novgorod well us  Ladoga look
влагу уже Новгород ну нас Ладога смотри
Ladoga was never a city at all
Ладога вообще городом никогда не было
Ladoga it was a transit point for these
Ладога это было перевалочный пункт этих
Vikings Yes small and a village there for
викингов Да небольшое и селение там на
10 houses No well from the point of view that
10 хат Не ну с точки зрения то что
speaking about Rurik It is clear that
говоря про Рюрика Это понятное дело это
Rurik is a myth Rurik is a myth Rurik that
Рюрик - это миф Рюрик миф Рюрик что
Rurik for example is found not only in
Рюрик например встречается не только в
our mythology that
нашей мифологии то
is that is so it is just well
есть то есть тако это просто ну просто
then the
потом
story was invented because it was fashionable to
повесть придумали потому что была мода
invent some kind of
придумывать этим князьям какие-то там
shorter
короче
genealogical years for these princes objectively This is a bad
родословных лет объективно Это плохой
source so look and besides this
источник вот так смотри а кроме этого
source there are no others that
источника никаких больше нету что там
Novgorod came to Kyiv from Novgorod
Новгород пришли в Киев из Новгорода
Ruriks and so on Further Yes this is the problem that is
рюрики и так Дале Да это проблема вот
precisely those years not
именно тех лет не
only more modern centuries
только более современ веков
know That is I just now have
знае То есть у меня сейчас как раз
some streamer from Ukraine pop and not
какому-то стримеру из Украины попа а не
streamers discussed with this that I
стримерши обсуждали с это то что я как
think that Kievan Rus has no
считаю то что у Киевской Руси нет
direct heir That is neither Russia nor
прямого наследника То есть ни Россия ни
Ukraine can be attributed to them Here we
Украина их нельзя отнести им Вот мы
inherit Rus Well it is clear Just
наследовать рус Ну ясно Так же так же
like for example
как например
Italy  is not a direct heir to the
Италия не есть прямым наследником
ladies' empire Yes, but but if we look,
дамской империи Да но но если мы смотрим
for example, the population of Italy is essentially the
например население Италии это по сути то
population that has lived there since time immemorial
население которое жило там испокон веков
Yes, these are the Heirs of those people, there is
Да это Наследники тех людей
no political continuity Directly
политически нету преемственности Прямо
from the Roman Empire, modern
от Римской империи современной
Italy,
Италия
but plus another That's why you can't call
но плюс ещ Вот почему нельзя называть
certain
наследниками те или иные
countries heirs 20 states
страны 20 государств
or but if we look, for example, people
или но если мы смотрим Да например люди
who lived on the territory of Rus', here is Kyiv
которые жили на территории Руси вот Киев
There and so on Yes, those people who
Там и так дальше Да те люди которые
now live in the Zhitomir region in the
сейчас живут в Житомирской области в
Kyiv region are essentially their Heirs Yes,
Киевской это по сути ихние Наследники Да
people, yes, people who lived in there, the
люди да люди которые жили в там
Vladimir region Yes, these Finno-
Владимирской области Да вот эти фино
Ugric tribes, people who now
угорские племена люди которые сечас Там
live there, these are their Heirs are those peoples
живут это ихни Наследник это те народы
who are just donkeys No,
которые просто осли Немен
he can somehow be an heir, but I
он может как-то быть наследником но я
mean a state, that is, a state
имею в виду государство то есть
Well, a state is not a
государство Ну государство не
state, look, the Russian
государство смотри российское
state appeared In the ninety-first
государство появилось В девяносто первом
year and Ukraine appeared in Denona too,
году и Украина появилось в денона тоже
in terms of the state, there is no heritage, that
вот в плане государства нет наследия то
is, the same thing as calling someone the
есть то же самое то что назвать кого-то
heir of the USSR, well, that's how Russia
наследником ССР это ну вот как россия
likes to say that we are Heirs with  no
любит говорить то что мы Наследники с не
they are not the Heirs with Yes here even if
они не Наследники с Да тут даже если
you look Russia was one of the first to leave
посмо Россия одна из первых вышла
firstly from the Union that is sa
во-первых с Союза то есть са
declared sovereignty in Denom year on
провозгласила суверенитет в Деном году
July 12 that is the last Here Kazakhstan came out
12 июля то есть последними Вот вышел
Kazakhstan Yes this point of view
Казахстан Казахстан Да это точки зрения
says that the Kazakhs are the Heirs of the Soviet Union
говорит что казахи - это Наследники сове
they were the last to come out Kazakhs often
они послед вышли казахи часто так и
say so even if so among the Kazakhs
говорят даже если так среди казахов
now well this is more Sol here are the Moldovan
сейчас ну это больше Сол вот Молдовы
generations what they like to say is that
поколения то что любят говорить то что
they are the Heirs of the Golden Horde And so it
они Наследники Золотой Орды А так и
is su the Golden Horde its core
есть су Золотая Орда её ядро это
was made up of Turkic peoples yes Basically
составляли тюркские народы да В основном
these Polovtsians Kipchaks
вот эти половцы кипчаки -
are modern Kazakhs modern there
это современные казахи современные там
this is Crimean Tatars part Yes
вот это Крымские татары часть Да
uh this Polovtsian Polovtsian steppe
ээ вот этот половецкий Половецкая степь
it was part of Ukraine where there is the
она ж была часть Украины где там
Kherson region Zaporozhye region
Херсонская область Запорожская область о
and there further all the way to Mongolia and these
и туда дальше аж до до Монголии и эти
territories they were there let's say for
территории они были там скажем
millennia uh migration routes of
тысячелетиями ээ миграционными путями
very many peoples If we look at the
очень многих народов Если мы смотрим
Huns Yes from there they went to the Roman Empire
гуны Да оттуда прошли до Римской империи
and then the Scythians there  all sorts of Sarmatians, Turks,
да потом скифы там всякие сарматы тюрки
and so on, that is, these territories, the
И так дальше то есть эти территории
Bulgarians as well. Yes, you know that near
Болгары также Да вот ты знаешь что возле
Zaporozhye, one of the Bulgarian kings,
Запорожья один из болгарских царей там
Asparukh was buried there. Well, by the way, I didnt know,
был похоронен аспарух Ну кстати не знал
well, wait a second or Asparukh and
ну сейчас подожди ещё раз или аспарух ан
Asparukh,
аспарух
Zaporozhye, yes, yes, yes, the proto Bulgarian Khan. Yes,
Запорожье дадада прото болгарский Хан Да
near this, the Bulgarians also once came
возле это Болгары тоже когда-то пришли
from there, from the Volga region. Yes, here in Panon,
оттуда из Поволжья Да ээ сюда в панон
or whatever its called, they passed
или как там она называется так прошли
through the steppes of modern Ukraine and in the
через степи современной Украины и в
Zaporozhye region. Yes, he was buried there.
районе Запорожья Да там похоронен был
In the twentieth century, his burial was found. There is
Вот в двадцатом веке был найден его
a lot of this. Yes, yes,
захоронение куча такого есть Ну да да
it changed very much. And the Kazakhs, it
это менялось очень си и казахи
turns out, well, there were no Kazakhs,
получается ну казахов как таких не было
just like there were no Ukrainians. Yes, in those
да также как не было украинцев Да в те
days, that is, there were Polovtsians there. Yes, these are
времена то есть тогда были там половцы
precisely the modern nationalities.
Да именно национальности современные
That is, it turns out, the Kazakhs. Yes, their
такие То есть получается казахи Да ихни
ancestors were of different genders. They
предки были там полов намер Они же
were called Kipchaks. They were also Cumans.
кипчаки назывались Да они же куманы вот
In Rus', they were called Polovtsians, there in
просто на Руси их называли половцы там в
Asia, they were called Kipchaks in Europe.  they
Азии их называли кипчаки в Европе их
were called Cumans
называли куманы
and But many, many of these Polos
и Но много много вот этих поло
they dissolved also in Hungary in
они растворились также в Венгрии в
Romania remained
Румынии оставались
Well, well, because really
Да вот ну потому что действительно
a nationality as which now they
национальность как которые сейчас их
then actually did not exist they are more
тогда фактически не было они более
Pol in itself a nationality Yes they
Поль само по себе национальности Да они
appeared in the era, let's say, after
появились в эпоху уже скажем так после
well in the bourgeois era That is, this is a
ну в буржуазную эпоху То есть это
product of bourgeois society before this there
продукт буржуазного общества до этого
was no national consciousness there
национального самосознания не было
were such regional ones There are
были вот такие региональные какие-то Там
tribal and so on yes, that is, they simply
племенные и так дальше да то есть просто
pushed off from something they could call themselves that
от чего-то отталкивались могли себя так
or well basically in fact
назвать либо ну в основном на са деле
they came up with the fact that someone
они же придумали то что кто-то кого-то
called someone that way that is how countries now
так назвал то есть как вот страны сейчас
differ in that we call them that and
отличаются тем то что мы называем так а
they call themselves generally differently because
они сами себя вообще по-другому называют
that is the same
пому то есть тот же
any Such a country is basically
любая Такая страна она в основном
called not as we are accustomed to
называется не так как у нас принято их
calling them Which is strange Well, well, just like the
называть Что странно Ну ну так же как
French Yes the Germans What they call
это французы Да немцев Как называют
the Alemanni Why Because the Germanic
алеман Почему Потому что германские
tribes of the Alemanni were and the
племена аллеманов было а во Францию
Germanic tribes of the Franks came to France that's
пришли племена франков германские вот и
all Well,
всё Ну
just now a lot of Russian
вот просто сейчас много Российская
Propaganda you see is starting to deduce So
Пропаганда видите начинает выводить Так
that supposedly Russia is this  there is almost a
что якобы Россия - это вот там чуть ли
direct Heir of Kievan Rus yes Well
не прямой Наследник Киевской Руси да Ну
yes a
да
failure and Ukraine is some kind of there
сбой а Украина - это какая-то там
It is not clear here are the Ukrainians that Lenin created
Непонятно вот украинцы что Ленин создал
Yes Lenin Lenin created the Austrian
Да Ленин Ленин создал австрийский
General Staff And so on Yes all sorts of such a
генштаб И так дальше Да всякие такие
joke either that Lenin created or that the
прикол либо то что Ленин создал либо то
Reich appeared in the General Staff Yes And so
что в генштабе появилось Рейха Да А так
like well yes this is the most popular thesis that
типа ну да это самый популярный тезис то
is but I have never watched
есть но я вообще ни разу не смотрел
TV at all
именно ТВ вообще
But here it is still clear
такое Но вот она всё равно просека то
that you go there to some
что ты заходишь там в какой-нибудь
tiktok there will definitely be something like that
tiktok там по-любому будет что-то вот
this is how they say you can not you
ска это так говорится ты можешь не ты
can not watch TV But in
можешь не смотреть телевизор Но ты в
life you meet these
жизни каждый день встречаешь этих
TV viewers every day like that yes yes yes that they are
телезрителей вот так да да да то что они
everywhere that is broadcast this
везде то есть транслируют это
yes full especially if you communicate with someone like that then
да полно особенно если так с кем-то
like for a long time
общаешься то типа давно в тикток тоже
you will also want to go to tiktok there Shaman is idolized Mizulina
захочешь там Шамана боготворят мизулина
and this is about Novgorod yes If I'm not
а вот это насчёт Новгорода да Если я не
mistaken then the Moscow kingdom or
ошибаюсь то Московское царство или
principality there it captured when the
княжество там оно же захватило когда
Novgorodians  almost the population of the Armed Forces Yes of
новгородцев чуть ли не ВС население Да
Novgorod itself yes There were always
самого Новгорода да Там постоянно
some genocides that is, both
какие-нибудь геноциды добыли то есть и
during baptism and during the capture of what even
при крещении и при захвате чего даже
when Kievan Rus it captured
когда Киевская Русь она кото захватывала
there were often
там часто были
during the times of Rus no
во времена Руси е
one would kill ordinary people Why
бы никто не убивал простых Люде Почему
Because they were essentially workers by
Потому что они были по сути рабочие
force give in Yes when this
силой поддай Да когда приходил этот
prince came he
князь он по
essentially killed the one who ruled there
сути как бы убивал того кто там
everything all the others if he strongly disagreed
всё все других если сильно не соглас
who there directly
который там прям
nevi Novgorod one
неви Новгороде
could say Moscow
бы можно сказать Москва
neb yes Moscow did not like it So Moscow
неб да Москва это не любила Вот и Москва
then came everything under itself then went further
потом пришла всё под себя дальше пошла
that is then it was already just these
то есть тогда же это уже как раз эти
centuries that more or less centralized such began to form
века стали образовываться более-менее
Well one can say a
централизованные такие Ну можно сказать
state but still there was This
государство но всё равно было Вот это
division Like if we take the territory of the
разделение Типа если брать территорию
current Russian Federation the Armed Forces
вот нынешней Российской Федерации ВС
were there and Vladimir in my opinion
равно там же были и Владимиром по-моему
somehow was the principality of Kato ne
как-то было княжество Като не
pommi sulye
помми сулье
principality Yes but the Novgorod region
княжество Да но Новгородская область
then oh the republic was big probably the
тогда ой республика была большой наверно
biggest at that time there is also Karelia
самом больша в то время там же и Карелия
Finland Estonia and so Along the sulfur
Финляндия Эстония и так Вдоль по серно
coast to
побережью с
decide That is now from the point of view That's
решать То есть сейчас с точки зрения Вот
how I live now Well Crimea Russia That's
как я сейчас живу то Ну Крым Россия Вот
exactly at the moment I went there I
именно в данный момент я туда ездил
didn't see anything like that but all
ничего там такого не видел но е все
disputed territories should be considered
спорные территории надо считать
a referendum under the supervision of an
референдумом под наблюдением
independent specialist the question so I'll
независимого специалиста вопрос так
clarify the city of Sudzha is Ukraine I
уточню город Суджа это Украина Я так
understand Yes in the Turkish region Well now
понимаю Да в туркой области Ну сейчас
it is occupied that is Crimea not stop in the
она оккупирована то есть Крым не стоп в
sense of occupied Well occupation is
смысле оккупирована Ну оккупация - это
temporary that is from your point of view Crimea is not
временно то есть с точки у тебя Крым не
occupied but the court is occupied why
оккупирован а суд же оккупирована почему
so Crimea is annexed
так Крым аннексированный
there for example
там например
that more went in their favor and so on
что больше в их пользу пошли и так далее
That is Ukraine as I understand they don't have
То есть Украина как я понимаю у них нету
exactly the goal that we Well and if in court
именно цели то что мы Ну а если в суд же
now hold a referendum What do you think the
сейчас провести референдум Как думаешь
result
какой результат
will be 100% that for Ukraine is
будет 100% то что за Украину
correct in the DPR that is well in Crimea I
правильно в ДНР то есть ну в Крыме
don't understand at all Look how can you
вообще не пони Вот смотри как можно
talk about some kind of referendum yes when
говорить О каком-то референдуме да когда
people who were
людей которые
for Ukraine were either expelled or killed or
за Украину либо изгнали либо убили либо
intimidated And so on and so on yes that is there  in
запугали И так дальше да то есть там по
fact there were no referendums That is, I
сути референдумов не было То есть я
say you say that there should be a
говорю ты кажеш что должен быть
referendum yes When Russia brought
референдум да Когда Россия в Крым навела
about a million people from other regions to Crimea
около миллиона людей из других регионов
Yes, what kind of referendum the problem is that they either
Да какой референдум проблема есть то что
evicted those who disagreed or left themselves
выселяли несогласных либо сами уходили
that is, during the time of this Donbass,
то есть во времена вот этого Донбасса
these 8 years there Well, many people came
вот эти 8 лет там Ну много же приезжал
constantly that is, there is a video there, of course, its
постоянно то есть видео там пож есть
just a fact that is, its hard to say
просто факт то есть тяжело сказать
at this moment But some kind of
именно на данный момент Но какой-никакой
democratic moment should still
демократический момент надо всё-таки
be tried to resolve because
попробовать решить потому что
well, theres only one democratic moment here like
ну демократический момент тут один типа
Russia takes your troops from Ukraine and
Россия забирает твои войска Из Украины а
Ukraine will then figure everything out thats
Украина дальше уже все разберётся вот и
all yes but I dont agree with Crimea
всё да но вот с Крымом не согласен По
Why Crimea somehow
что Крым А почему Крым как-то уже
has already taken shape what does it mean taken shape wait
сложилось что значит сложилось подожди
whats in your head
что у тебя в голове
kr Well, because in Crimea I
кры Ну потому что в Крыму я точно
dont know the circumstances exactly That is, how it
обстоятельства не знаю То есть как
took place All this is that they just
проходил Вот это всё то что ну просто
came and took it, whats the difference it took place
пришли взяли это какая разница проходила
according to all international documents its
по всем международным документам это
Ukraine everything is not well that is, not just for
Украина всё не ну то есть не просто к
example as it took place in the LPR DPR Well, in
примеру как проходило в лнр ДНР Ну вот
these regions in Donbass in short Well, I think
этих областях на донбасе короче Ну думаю
you heard  that there it was simply possible to
ты слышал то что там просто можно было
Priti vote one for five
Прити проголосовать одному за пять
people there was no difference again again
человек не было кая разница ещё раз ещё
what difference does it make how to vote and in
раз какая разница как проголосовать и в
Donetsk and in Lugansk and in Crimea this
Донецке и в Луганске и в Крыме это уже
was already after the Russian occupation all
было после российской оккупации всё
What referendums under what laws Well that
Какие референдумы по Каким законам Ну то
is, armed people came look in
есть пришли вооружённые люди смотри у
your Russia for example now in St. Petersburg
вас в России например сейчас в Питере на
no one will come out to a rally with
митинг никто не выйдет потому что с
leaflets because they will immediately have a baton shoved under
листочками ему сразу дубинку засунут под
their tonsils And what can you say when
самой гланды А что говорить когда
armed people are supposedly on your
вооружённые люди типа есть на твоих
streets So damn it is not a referendum it
улицах Так что блин не референдум он
should take place Specifically under the supervision
должен проходить Именно под надзором
of the ref Listen, how do you feel about the
о реф Слушай а как ты относишься к
referendum on the independence of Tatarstan
референдуму о независимости Татарстана
Bashkortostan calmly if an
Башкортостана спокойно если вот проведён
honest referendum is held then everything is checked then
честный референдум то всё проверено то а
why in Russia they do not allow
Поче почему в России не разрешают
all these republics to hold a referendum
провести референдум всем этим
to the Russian government and there are so
республикам к Российской власти и так
many questions that is, it is impossible to say
много вопросов то есть нельзя сказать то
that I basically came up with some kind of
что я вот в принципе сосен с каким-либо
statement not if there were some kind of
заявлением не если бы были какие-то вот
mass desire to separate, in the sense of
массовые желания отделиться ли в смысле
mass mass  there are simply desires, anyone
мас массовые желания есть просто любой
who opens their mouth gets jailed for
кто открывает рот его садят за
it Well, I don't know, I don't listen, everyone wants
это Ну не знаю я не сл все все хотят
ambassadors to send Moscow Where next and live
послы послать Москву Куда дальше и жить
without it Everyone is simply afraid to talk about it
без неё Все просто боятся про это
because
говорить потому что
the SSb is not Well, here is separation, in principle, from
ссб не Ну вот отделение в принципе с
some country But it should be decided, in
какой-то страны Но должно решаться в
principle, democratically, not like it was, like
принципе демократически не так как было
let's shoot, let's bring in
то что давайте постреляем вот введём
troops, plus Russian troops were brought in, that is,
войска плюс войска России ввели то есть
but this is wrong Well, in principle, this is
но это неправильно Ну в принципе это
a war, this is
война это
wrong, but this is not Well, what do you
неправильно вот а так не Ну а как ты
think is the reason for this War
считаешь из-за чего эта Война
Well, because Putin wants
идёт Ну из-за того то что Путин хочет
Precisely his influence on Ukraine, that
Вот именно своё влияние на Украину то
is, morally, so that there is no NATO there
есть морально то чтобы никакого там НАТО
Well, you are
Ну вы
ours, as
наши как
such, how else is it right Well, kry is part of
такая как ещё правильно Ну кры это часть
this strategy, that is, in 2014, he
этой стратегии то есть в 2014 году он
seized Crimea, like,
захватил Крым типа
well, in 2014, Putin seized Crimea as
ну в 2014 году Путин захватил Крым в
part of this same strategy Well,
рамках этой же стратегии Ну
yes, but there was unrest in Crimea and before that
да но на Крыму были волнения и до именни
What is What does unrest mean Well, as
Что такое Что значит волнение Ну как
if there were no That's what what will you
если бы не было Вот это что что ты
say, you'll get a baton in your mouth
скажешь дубинку в рот
For example, if in Tatarstan
получишь Например если бы в Татарстане
they came out  mass such we want to
вот вышли массовые такие мы хотим
separate here is this unrest that is
отделиться вот вот это волнение то есть
not and what unrest was there in Crimea before the
не а какие в Крыму волнения были до
arrival of the Russian army Well there were
прихода российской армии Ну были
pro-Russian ones connected with Euromaidan that
пророссийские связаны с Евромайдана то
is well there is what is unrest What is
есть ну есть что такое волнение Что
unrest there were the same rallies
такое волнение были теже самые митинги
remember there The thing is that look rally
помин воне Дело в том что смотри митинг
Yes and you in Russia a little bit do not understand this
Да и вам в России немножко это не понять
in Ukraine the concept of rally Yes with us uh
в Украине понятие митинг Да у нас э
anyone came out whenever you want and
выходили кто хочешь Когда хочешь и
held rallies for example someone is for
проводили митинги например кто-то за
Europe someone is against this is normal this is
Европу кто-то против это нормально это
not
не
unrest No well well this is yes well if if
волнение Не ну ну это да ну если если
there are people who Yes and if you look
есть люди которые Да и если посмотреть
then uh in Crimea pro-Russian parties
то ээ в Крыму пророссийские партии
gained no more than 2% even With all yes I
набирали не больше 2% даже При всём да
looked that in Donbass there was no
смотрел то что и на Донбассе не было вот
this pro-Russian yes there were no
этого пророссийских да не было никаких
yes like there was a regional party it
да типа там партия региона это
was Donbass essentially such Yes but it is
была Донбасская по сути такая Да но это
not pro-Russian
не пророссийская
it is not directly a lot and there is in
она не прямо много и набирала есть на
Donbass It gained a lot in Donbass
Донбассе Она много набирала на Донбассе
it was a monopolist there they gained in
она монополистом была там набирали
different ways they
разными путями
gained this no Well by the way I don't have
набирали это да не Ну кстати у меня не
at all  I was the only one, probably,
вообще я был единствен как наверно свя
directly connected with propaganda, that's what
напрямую с пропагандой вот это то что у
I have relatives from Ukraine Well, from
меня родственники из Украины есть Ну с
Donbass, that is My
Донбасса именно то есть У меня
grandmother, you know, the Don Cossacks Yes, yes,
бабушка знаешь таки донские казаки Да да
my grandmother is a Don Cossack and
у меня вот бабушка Донского казак и там
everything is according to her and my grandfather is Russian
все по ней а дедушка дедушка русский
Pony head Cossack woman not a Cossack oh yes
Поня башка Казачка не казак ой да
Cossack
казаче
sl that's about the Russian side just Yeah,
сл то про российскую сторону как раз Угу
that is exactly what it was That's what I
то есть именно было Вот это то что мне в
basically don't like such rhetoric, that
принципе не нравится такая риторика то
the bad ones have come to usurp us,
что вот плохих пришли нас узурпировать
that is, well, that's what I've heard
то есть нун такой Я наслышан с детства
from her since childhood I'll say so, you know, a grandmother
от неё был я скажу так знаешь бабушка
will come to Ukraine and a grandmother will
придёт Украины и бабушка будет
tell how good it is here and how bad it
рассказывать как хорошо тут и как плохо
was under Russia, not exactly a grandmother By the way,
было при России не именно бабушка Кстати
she doesn't live there I have distant
она не живёт Там у меня дальние
relatives from there and my grandmother lives
родственники оттуда а бабушка она живёт
in the Novgorod region,
как раз в Новгородской области
she actually came from there but it's just
она вообще приехала оттуда но просто вот
that kind of rhetoric, I haven't
такое вот такая риторика она у меня была
heard it since childhood But like I
с детстве на слышна Но типа я её никак
don't support it in any way But that's the
не поддерживаю Но вот ну то есть
only thing I know about it That is,
единственное что я про это знаю То есть
I don't really  I talked to this distant
я не особо общался с этим дальне
relative that during just
родственником то что во время как раз
these Donbass history 8 years
вот этих донбасской всей истории 8 лет
that in the fourteenth year shells flew from Ukraine to
то что в четырнадцатом году с Украины по
our house around Yeah the
дому нашему прилетели снаряды вокруг Угу
only one with this What do you think
единственный с этим Как ты думаешь
why in 2014 shells flew to the house
почему в 2014 году по дому прилетели
Well because just the Russian
снаряды Ну потому что как раз Российская
Federation was waging Well first
Федерация вела Ну сначала начались
just such local just war began already The
просто такие местные просто война уже
war was going on Russian troops were and
Шла война российские войска были и
just were Yes absolutely but rather a
просто были Да абсолютно а скорее
civil war in the sense of a civil
Гражданская война в смысле гражданская
war again Well that well from the point of
война ещё раз Ну то что ну с точки
view Russia officially was not again
зрения Россия официально не была ещё раз
we do not say officially unofficially
мы же не говорим официально неофициально
Yes if I do not declare a duel to you yes
Да если я не объявлю тебе дуэль тебе да
this is a fight or do we need an official fight
это драка есть или нуж официальная драка
and Well by the way from the point of view Well yes officially I
а Ну кстати с точки Ну да официально
said it incorrectly because now
неправильно сказал потому что и сейчас
officially as if there is no war now
официально как бы не идёт Война сейчас
this is a special military operation there is
это специально воена операции никакой
no civil war before the arrival of
Гражданской войны нет до прихода
Russian troops there yes on April 12
российских войск туда да 12 апреля
fourteenth in Donbas everything was
четырнадцатого года на Донбассе всё было
calm Well so no Well there were these
спокойно Ну так не Ну были вот эти
seizures there like Euromaidan only
захваты там по типа Евромайдана только
dial again again  look there were rallies were
набо ещё раз ещё раз смотри митинги были
going to it's all normal armed
собирались это всё нормально вооружён
armed seizures Like they started on
вооружённые захваты Типа начали 12
April 12 Yes the chronology is accurate April 12
апреля Да хронология точна 12 апреля
this Strelkov enters Slavyansk and
этот э стрелков заходит в Славянск и
starts to seize Gorlovka and others
начинает захватывать Горловку и другие
yes dgo is going to Slavyansk and other
да дго собирается Славянск и другие
military precisely a clash And about the seizure of
военные именно столкновение А про захват
administrative tasks I don't remember
административных заданий я не помню
administrative Yes this these are
административных Да это это это
just political protests yes this is
политические просто протесты да это
normal yes for example now there in
нормально да например сейчас там в
Europe There these protesters can run into the building
Европе Там могут в здание забежать эти
here this is normal for
протестующие у нас это это нормально для
you it's just wild for Russians you don't
вас дико просто для россиян вы не
understand how Well by the way yes we have such
понимаете как Ну кстати да у нас такого
Well they came Yes the protesters came like into
Ну зашли Да зашли протестующие типа в
this into the building demanding something from these and
этот в здание требуют что-то от эти и
what well by the way in this regard there
что ну на кстати в этом плане
was really a problem that Well
действительно проблема было то что Ну
even here's what I didn't understand in the twenties
даже вот чего Я не понимал в двадцатых
we had rallies why Well yes
же годах у нас митинги были поему Ну да
the twenties that they kind of pass peacefully
двадцатые что они как бы мирно проходят
all these peaceful actions didn't really
вот эти все мирные акции не особо
take into account that is countries when they come at you
воспринимал то есть стран когда на тебя
with a truncheon And you just
идут с дубинкой А ты просто плакатом
stand there with a poster that is somehow in this regard it's
стоишь то есть у нас как-то в этом плане
not the same with us  we have the only one when
не то есть у нас единственное когда вот
under the Russian Federation they were able to
при Российской Федерации смогли морально
somehow morally put pressure on the protesters, that was the time of
как-то надавить митингующие это времена
Bolotnaya Square, that is, the only
Болотной площади то есть единственное
thing they could achieve there was then
что там че могли добиться это тогда было
and then the oppositionists took and said to
и то оппозиционеры взяли и сказали
disband everyone Yes, that is, they talked with Putin, they
распустили всех Дада то есть с Путиным
adopted something there and that is
поговорили что-то там приняли
exactly what we have Well, yes, in
вот а так именно у нас Ну да у нас в
principle, we have such a culture of protest rallies,
принципе культура такая митингов
it is so for us to look at something that
она так для нас вот смотреть на такое
can come
что вот может выйти
out with
выска с
weapons, not with weapons, it is not a rally with
оружием не с оружием это не митинг с
weapons, what do these people say, "Amen,"
оружием что гово эти зах амини
look, that is not yet, that is, these are people At the rally
смотри ещ не то есть это люди На митинг
Yes, they broke into the building and there they
Да там ворвались в здание и там что-то
shout something, that's all they came to Donetsk What was
кричат вот и всё в Донецке пришли Что
there to
там
shout about, no, I didn't really like delve
покричать не вот я не особо типа вникал
into that, although I watched some
именно в то хотя я смотрел некоторое
videos, but I only watched one person, you know, fanova, I
видео но так я только одного человека
only watched his video, but
фано вот я только у него смотрел а
Tefanovo, no Listen, you know,
тефаново да не Послушай ты знаешь
fanovaya says everything, that is, precisely
фановая всё говорит то есть именно
chronologically That is, he has some
хронологическом То есть у него каких-то
inaccuracies or inclinations about who or what
неточностей либо склонений кто или
side, but that's me  sometimes it happens
стороны нету но это я е иногда бывает
I'll look I
посмотрю
got it Okay let's run further let's In
понял Хорошо давай побегу дальше давай
short, something is not completely systematized in his
Короче что-то у него там не до конца В
head
голове
like a like a squeak a comment a
систематизировано так лайк писка комент
letter on y Instagram I don't know why
пись на й Instagram Я не знаю для чого
it's for you why else you should watch on
це тоб для чого ще тоб там дивитись на
my face But for you it's one two
оцей мий фейс Але для тебе це один два
or three clicks and you try me and I'll be a
або три клика а ты тримае мене и я буду
CTA in me there Kupa follower and I'll
КТА в мене там Купа фолловер и в мене
be in a cool mood to do New
буде класний настрой щоб робити Нови
cool video letter on my Instagram Popik
крут вдео пись на мий Instagram Попик
Andriy that's
Андрий вот
it let's go I'm
так давай я тебя
waiting for you N
чекаю N